Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush...
Wasn't there something else?
Huh!?
Rin, don't go and pull disappearing acts like that!
It scares me!
Okay.
Daikichi, pick a green one.
Come on. We're going.
It'll be safer if we hold hands while we walk.
Safer for me?
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
I want the blue one!
Since when were there so many parents with children here?
I want that one!
This?
Yeah.
Um... Okay. Looks good.
What size are you?
Don't know.
Rin, turn around.
Like this?
What am I supposed to be comparing it to?
Don't know!
Quit waving your arms around!
What else do you need?
Pyjamas! Pants! Shirts! Socks!
You don't want a skirt?
You've only put trousers in here.
They don't let us wear skirts to nursery.
I see...
Nursery!?
I completely forgot!
Tomorrow's Monday, isn't it?
I'm tired, Daikichi!
It's just a little further. Be strong.
Okay...
I'm starving.
We're almost home, so...
Okay...
Are you bunking off again?
You good for nothing...
You're always bringing me stuff I don't need.
I'm going to get mad!
What's that supposed to mean? Damn idiot!
Hey!
Get your hands off me!
Let go!
Um... Excuse me...
Yes, this is the Maeda residence.
Oh, hello. I heard about your recent loss, I'm sorry.
Yes, please wait a moment.
Haruko-san? It's Daikichi-san.
Coming! Thanks!
Oh? Haruko?
Sorry, I never asked for your mobile number.
It's fine.
How do you go about starting nursery?
Nursery?
What!? You actually took Rin-chan home with you!?
Is it really okay?
For now.
What do you mean by "for now"?
Anyway, it's too late for me to take the day off tomorrow.
So what's the procedure to enrol her?
You can't just enrol her right away, you know.
Can't you pull some strings?
I'm not sure I'm the right person to be asking.
You could start by asking someone at the city hall.
It's Sunday night.
What is it!?
No, just something on my end.
Mama, is that Rin-chan?
Are you okay?
Rin-chan!
Hey, Reina!
We're talking about something important.
Rin-chan!
There's a temporary nursery for emergencies...
A temporary nursery for emergencies?
Rin-chan!
What is it, Dai-chan?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Ah, no, just something on my end.
I'll be done in a minute. Just wait a bit.
I can't wait!
Haruko-san, I'm taking the miso soup off the stove.
Oh! Thank you.
Hey, it sounds like you're pretty busy, so I'll call back la-
Rin-chan!
Emergency temporary nursery
Man, hardly any results...
So, suddenly I'm going to double my work commute?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm fine.
This one's pretty close, but I can't get out of work at six.
Yeah. Sure. Let's play again sometime.
Yeah. Bye bye, Reina-chan! See you!
This one looks pretty good,
but it says they'll only take kids on emergency notice for ten days.
A bath...
Wait just a little longer.
Daikichi! Daikichi!
It's morning...
Right... Sorry...
Did you sleep here?
The futon feels strangely warm.
Take this off!
Right, right...
So, about the nursery you're going to today...
Thanks for the food!
Thanks for the food...
Elbows off the table while you eat!
Right. Sorry.
The nursery you're going to is only
taking you on a temporary basis, okay?
Temporary?
It means you'll go there until we can find a place to formally enrol you at.
What does "formally" mean?
It means properly.
Well, it's slightly different...
Hey, my hair's fine!
Are you okay?
I'm... fine...
I-I'm fine...
I can see it!
P-Put me down! Put me down!
What? What?
Is it embarrassing for you to have other kids see me carrying you?
Daikichi...
S-Sorry...
Please take good care of her, then.
We will. Take care.
Don't give me that look.
I won't be able to make it back while it's light,
but I'll try to be as quick as I can.
I promise.
It's a pinky promise.
If I tell a lie, I'll absolutely swallow a thousand needles.
Damn it!
My finger was cut off!
You got the song wrong.
See you. Wait for me, Rin.
I'm sorry, Rin. I never thought about how you felt.
You had no understanding of your mum's
circumstances, nor of my granddad's lifespan.
You only knew the pain of being left alone.
Did you think I was going to leave you behind, as well?
I'm sure having that happen to you once...
...is more than enough to last you a lifetime.
Read this to me.
Sure!
Kawachi-san, let's grab some lunch.
Oh, I've got something here.
I got mine a little earlier.
I see. Then I'll be back in a bit.
The first day of the month and you're already in workaholic mode, huh?
It's not like that.
Get me a photo of this sample.
Will do.
Kawachi-san! There's a call for you on line four about the investors' inspection.
Coming.
This is Kawachi.
Bye bye!
Let's keep going!
Yeah.
Kawachi...
Yes? Sorry...
You're late!
Sorry, sorry...
Go and get changed.
Okay!
Rin-chan, don't break it, okay?
Bye bye!
Bye bye...
Hello? Just a moment.
Kawachi-san?
It's Miyata-san from Mitsutomo Trading.
I'll take it.
Yes? This is Kawachi.
Thank you very much.
Yes, this is Kawachi.
Yes.
I'm terribly sorry.
I'll be done at work in just a little bit.
I'm sorry.
The nursery is... so far away!
Rin! Sorry I'm late.
Welcome back.
I'm so... sorry...
Rin.
Oh, are those crisps? They look good!
Chopped vegetables!
Daikichi
I swallowed...
...a thousand needles!
Okay, I'll leave this to you.
Kawachi-san! You need to sign here!
It's not like it's actually likely,
but what if I find a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Right... Sorry...
Kawachi. This was supposed to go out yesterday, right?
Whoa!
I'm so sorry...
This really isn't like you.
Sorry...
I've already apologised to the recipient, so...
I'm sorry. I'll call them immediately.
Let's go for a few drinks. It's been a while.
Sorry, tonight's no good.
Then how about tomorrow?
I've got something going on then, as well.
Oh, I get it. Sounds like someone's getting lucky.
Get on.
I'm fine.
Daikichi?
Hold on tight!
Daikichi! Run away from the moon!
Here goes!
mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm
Baby Bear and the Acorns
There's just no end to this!
How long can I keep living like this?
Mother and Child Health Record
These are Rin-chan's things.
This is all that she has.
Her mother and child health record and
other important documents are here, too.
Even if it's only for a short while,
raising a child is a terribly difficult job.
Surely, Rin is the one who has it the hardest.
Sorry, but I'm just going to have a little look in here.
Her mouth's still the same.
All of the relatives talk about you
like you're some sort of supervillain.
But I wonder... Who's the real villain, Masako-san?
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
What's wrong? Feeling sick?
So you've decided to sleep over there aft-
Huh!?
What!? D-Did I...?!
It's sweat!
Sure, sure.
It's sweat. Sweat.
I'll change the sheets, so give me a hand.
I said that it's sweat!
And I agreed!